Ph.D. CANDIDATE · BIOSIGNAL/DATA SCIENTIST

222, Wangsimni-ro 222, Seongdong-qu, Seoul, 04763, SOUTH KOREA

□ (+82) 10-4037-2405 | Moseungcha@gmail.com | HoseungCha | Hoseungcha | Incheseungcha | Inche

"The first step is to establish that something is possible; then probability will occur."

Summary

Ph.D @ Hanyang university. 7+ years of experience analyzing in biosignal/data such as electromyogram (EMG), electroeculogram (EOG), electroenchpahlogram (EEG), etc. My research topics include myoelectric control, brain-computer interfacing, and computational neuroscience. Skilled in the application of machine learning or deep learning algorithms using Matlab and Python. I have developed various real-time biosignal-based applications such as 1) facial expression recognition system based on EMG [Click], 2) silent speech recognition system based on EMG, 3) lip shape recognition system based on EMG [Click], 4) Triple blink detection system based on EOG [Click], etc.

Experiences

Bio-Interfaced Translational Nanoengineering Group @ Georgia Tech

Atlanta, GA, USA

(Projected) Jan 2021 - Jan 2022

Postdoctoral Researcher Candidate
• Prof. Woon-Hong Yeo's Lab [Click]

Computational Neuroengineering Lab @ Hanyang University

Seoul, S.Korea

POSTDOCTORAL RESEARCHER

Sep 2020 - (Projected) Dec 2020

• Prof. Chang-Hwan Im's Lab [Click]

Computational Neuroengineering Lab @ Hanyang University

Seoul, S.Korea

POSTGRADUATE RESEARCHER

Sep 2015 - Feb 2016

• Prof. Chang-Hwan Im's Lab [Click]

Computational Neuroengineering Lab @ Hanyang University

Seoul, S.Korea

Undergraduate Researcher

Mar 2013 - Aug 2013

• Prof. Chang-Hwan Im's Lab [Click]

Tiol. Chang Hwalthins Lab [Click]

Education

Hanyang University Seoul, S.Korea

Ph.D. in Biomedical Engineering, GPA: 98.9/100

Mar 2016 - Aug 2020

• Thesis: Development of Face-Machine Interfaces Using Facial Electromyogram for Interactive Virtual Reality Applications

Hanyang University Seoul, S.Korea

M.S. IN BIOMEDICAL ENGINEERING, GPA: 98.2/100

Sep 2013 - Aug 2015

• Thesis: Development of a transient visual evoked potential (tVEP)-based brain switch system [Click]

Yonsei University Wonju, S.Korea Wonju, S.Korea

B.S. IN BIOMEDICAL ENGINEERING, GPA: 95/100

Mar 2008 - Aug 2013

• Received four scholarships for excellence in grades in 2009 and 2010 (total four semesters)

Honors & Awards

2019	Best Paper Award, 55th Korean Society of Medical & Biological Engineering [Click]	Incheon, S. Korea
2019	Best Poster Paper Award, 54th Korean Society of Medical & Biological Engineering [Click]	Yeosu, S. Korea
2018	Young Investigator Award, SMIT2018-IBEC2018 Joint Conference [Click]	Seoul, S. Korea
2018	Young Investigator Travel Award, SMIT2018-IBEC2018 Joint Conference [Click]	Seoul, S. Korea
2016	Best Poster Award, International Biomedical Engineering Conference [Click]	Seoul, S. Korea
2015	Excellence Poster Paper Award , 50th Korean Society of Medical & Biological Engineering [Click]	Daegu, S. Korea
2010	Highest honor (top 1% students for 2010 spring semester), Yonsei University	Wonju, S.Korea

PUBLISHED

11. **Ho-Seung Cha**, Seong-Jun Choi, and Chang-Hwan Im*, Real-time Recognition of Facial Expressions using Facial Electromyograms Recorded around the Eyes for Social Virtual Reality Applications

IEEE Access, vol. 8, pp. 62065-62075, Mar. 2020. [Link]

10. **Ho-Seung Cha**, Chang-Hee Han, and Chang-Hwan Im*, Prediction of Individual User's Dynamic Ranges of EEG Features from Resting-State EEG Data for Evaluating Their Suitability for Passive Brain–Computer Interface Applications

Sensors, vol. 20(4), pp. 988, Feb. 2020. [Link]

9. Seonghun Park, **Ho-Seung Cha**, and Chang-Hwan Im*, Development of an Online Home Appliance Control System Using Augmented Reality and an SSVEP-Based Brain–Computer Interface

IEEE Access, vol. 7, pp. 163604-163614, Nov. 2019. [Link]

8. Do Yeon Kim, Jinuk Kwon, Joo-Young Kim, **Ho-Seung Cha**, Yong-Wook Kim, In Young Kim, and Chang-Hwan Im*, New Method for Pure-Tone Audiometry Using Electrooculogram: A Proof-of-Concept Study

Sensors, vol. 18, Art.No.3651, Oct. 2018. [Link]

7. Jeong-Hwan Lim, Yong-Wook Kim, Jun-Hak Lee, Kwang-Ok An, Han-Jeong Hwang, **Ho-Seung Cha**, Chang-Hee Han, and Chang-Hwan Im, An emergency call system for patients in locked-in state using an SSVEP-based brain switch

Psychophysiology, vol. 54, pp. 1632-1634, May 2017. [Link]

6. Han-Jeong Hwang, Chang-Hee Han, Jeong-Hwan Lim, Yong-Wook Kim, Soo-In Choi, Kwang-Ok An, Jun-Hak Lee, Ho-Seung Cha, Seung Hyun Kim, and Chang-Hwan Im*, Clinical Feasibility of Brain-Computer Interface Based on Steady-State Visual Evoked Potential in Patients with Locked-in Syndrome: Case Studies

Psychophysiology, vol. 54, pp. 444-451, Dec. 2016. [Link]

5. Won-Du Chang, **Ho-Seung Cha**, Do Yeon Kim, Seung Hyun Kim, Chang-Hwan Im*, Development of an electrooculogram-based eye-computer interface for communication of individuals with amyotrophic lateral sclerosis

Journal of NeuroEngineering and Rehabilitation, vol. 14, Art. ID 89, Sep. 2017. [Link]

4. Won-Du Chang, **Ho-Seung Cha**, Chany Lee, Hoon-Chul Kang, and Chang-Hwan Im*, Automatic Identification of Interictal Epileptiform Discharges in Secondary Generalized Epilepsy

Computational and Mathematical Methods in Medicine, vol. 2016, Art. ID 8701973, Jun. 2016. [Link]

3. Won-Du Chang, **Ho-Seung Cha**, Kiwoong Kim, Chang-Hwan Im*, Detection of eye blink artifacts from single prefrontal channel electroencephalogram

Sensors, vol. 124, pp. 19-30, Feb. 2016. [Link]

2. Won-Du Chang, **Ho-Seung Cha**, Chang-Hwan Im*, Removing the Interdependency between Horizontal and Vertical Eye-Movement Components in Electrooculograms

Sensors, vol. 16(2), pp. 227, Feb. 2016. [Link]

1. **Ho-Seung Cha**, Won-Du Chang, YoungSeok Shin, and Chang-Hwan Im*, EEG-based neurocinematics: challenges and prospects

Brain-Computer Interfaces, vol. 2(4), pp. 186-192, Feb. 2016. [Link]

SUBMITTED

2. **Ho-Seung Cha** and Chang-Hwan Im*, Performance enhancement of facial electromyogram-based facial-expression recognition for social virtual reality applications using linear discriminant analysis adaptation

Virtual Reality, Submitted

1. **Ho-Seung Cha**, Won-Du Chang, and Chang-Hwan Im*, Deep-Learning-Based Real-Time Silent Speech Recognition using Facial Electromyogram Recorded Around Eyes for Hands-Free Interfacing in Virtual Reality Environment

IEEE Transactions on Emerging Topics in Computing, Under review

INTERNATIONAL

14. **Ho-Seung Cha**, Seongjun Choi, Chunghwan Kim, and Chang-Hwan Im, Real-time Electromyogram-Based Facial Expression Recognition Using Riemannian Geometry Features for VR application

Engineering in circadian rhythm and ubiquitous healthcare (Uhealthcare), Seoul, South Korea, December 6, 2020

13. **Ho-Seung Cha**, Seongjun Choi, and Chang-Hwan Im, Real-Time Electromyogram-Based Facial Expression Recognition Using Riemannian Geometry Features for VR Applications

41st International Engineering in Medicine and Biology (IEEE EMBC), Berlin, Germany, July 26, 2019

12. **Ho-Seung Cha** and Chang-Hwan Im*, New Strategy for Minimizing Training Time In EMG-Based Facial Expression Recognition for Virtual Reality Applications

SMIT2018-IBEC2018 Joint Conference, Seoul, South Korea, November 9, 2018.

11. Seongjun Choi, **Ho-Seung Cha**, and Chang-Hwan Im, User Authentication for Virtual Reality Applications Based on Facial EMG Induced by Facial Expression Changes

40th International Conference of the IEEE EMBS, Honolulu, USA, July 18, 2018

10. **Ho-Seung Cha** and Chang-Hwan Im, Prediction of individual user's suitability for passive BCI applications using short resting EEG recordings

7th International BCI Meeting, Pacific Grove, California, USA, May 22, 2018

9. Ho-Seung Cha, Won-Du Chang and Chang-Hwan Im, Real-time recognition of lip gestures based on facial EMG

3rd Annual International Biomedical Engineering Conference, Seoul, Korea, November 11, 2016

8. Ho-Seung Cha, Won-Du Chang and Chang-Hwan Im, A Real-Time Lip Gesture Recognition System using Facial EMG

38th Annual International Conference of the IEEE EMBS, Orlando, Florida, USA, August 19, 2016

7. Won-Du Chang, **Ho-Seung Cha**, and Chang-Hwan Im, Improved Electrooculogram-based Eye-writing Recognition Using a New Feature Extraction Method

2nd Annual International Biomedical Engineering Conference, Gyeongju, Korea, November 12, 2015

6. **Ho-Seung Cha** and Won-Du Chang, Young-Seok Shin, Dongpyo Jang and Chang-Hwan Im, EEG-Based Neurocinematics: Potential Brain Indices for Rating Films

 $37 th \, Annual \, International \, Conference \, of \, the \, IEEE \, EMBS, \, Milano, \, Italy, \, Aug \, 25 - 29, \, 2015 \, Italy, \, Aug \,$

 Jeong-Hwan Lim, Yong-Wook Kim, Chang-Hee Han, Ho-Seung Cha, and Chang-Hwan Im, An Emergency Call System for Patients with Severe ALS Using Less-Stimulating SSVEP-Based Brain Switch

37th Annual International Conference of the IEEE EMBS, Milano, Italy, Aug 2015

4. Won-Du Chang, **Ho-Seung Cha** and Chang-Hwan Im Kang, and Chang-Hwan Im*, A New Method for Detecting Eye-Blink Artifacts from a single-Channel Electroencephalogram

36th Annual International Conference of the IEEE EMBS, Illinois USA, Aug 2014

3. Won-Du Chang, **Ho-Seung Cha**, and Chang-Hwan Im*, Enhanced Template Matching Using Dynamic Positional Warping for Pattern Recongnition in Electroencephalogram

36th Annual International Conference of the IEEE EMBS, Chicago, Illinois USA, August 2014

2. Jeong-Hwan Lim, Jun-Hak Lee, Yong-Wook Kim, Han Choi, Chang-Hee Han, **Ho-Seung Cha**, and Chang-Hwan Im*, Implementation of a Steady State Visual Evoked Potential (SSVEP)-Based Online Brain-Switch System Using a Chromatic Stimulus

36th Annual International Conference of the IEEE EMBS, Chicago, Illinois USA, Aug 2014.

1. **Ho-Seung Cha**, Jeong-Hwan Lim, Chang-Hee Han, Han-Jeong Hwang, Won-Du Chang and Chang-Hwan Im*, A transient visual evoked potential (tVEP)-based brain switch system

DOMESTIC (S. KOREA)

- 11. **Ho-Seung Cha** and Chang-Hwan Im, development of sislent speech recognition system based on facial electromyogram recorded around eyes for hands-free interactions in virtual environments.
 - 55th Korean Society of Medical & Biological Engineering (KOSOMBE), Inchon, Korea, Nov 7, 2019
- 10. Kang-min Choi, **Ho-Seung Cha**, and Chang-Hwan Im, Real-time eye gaze tracking method using electrooculogram signals recorded around eyes in virtual environments
 - 55th Korean Society of Medical & Biological Engineering (KOSOMBE), Inchon, Korea, Nov 7, 2019
- 9. Jung-Hwan Kim, **Ho-Seung Cha**, Seoungjae Lee, Chuljin Park, In Young Kim, Se-Keun Park, and Chang-Hwan Im, Development of dyslexia diagnosis system using electrooculogram: a proof-of-concept study
 - 55th Korean Society of Medical & Biological Engineering (KOSOMBE), Inchon, Korea, Nov 7, 2019
- 8. Seong-Jun Choi, Chunghwan Kim, **Ho-Seung Cha**, and Chang-Hwan Im, Development of facial motion capture technology based on facial electromyogram using deep learning
 - 54th Korean Society of Medical & Biological Engineering (KOSOMBE), Inchon, Korea, Nov 7, 2019
- 7. **Ho-Seung Cha**, and Chang-Hwan Im, Development of avatar expressing emotions in real time using facial electromyogram-based facial expression in virtual environment
 - 54th Korean Society of Medical & Biological Engineering (KOSOMBE), Yeosu, S. Korea, May 9, 2019
- 6. **Ho-Seung Cha**, Seong-Jun Choi, Hodam Kim, and Chang-Hwan Im, Classification performance comparison for facial expression recognition based on surface electromyogram
 - 52th Korean Society of Medical & Biological Engineering (KOSOMBE), Chenbuk university, Cheonbuk, S. Korea, Nov 11 2017
- 5. **Ho-Seung Cha**, Won-Du Chang, Young Seok Shin, Dong Pyo Jang, and Chang-Hwan Im, Neurocinematics: development of indices of evaluating cinematic using EEG
 - 51th Korean Society of Medical & Biological Engineering (KOSOMBE), Bukyeong University, Pusan, S. Korea, May 13 2016
- 4. Jeong-Hwan Lim, Yong-Wook Kim, Jun-Hak Lee, **Ho-Seung Cha**, and Chang-Hwan Im, Development of less-stimulating brain-switch system using chromatic stimulus-induced steady-state state visual evoked potential
 - 50th Korean Society of Medical & Biological Engineering (KOSOMBE), Daegu, S. Korea, May 8, 2015
- 3. Ho-Seung Cha, JongYoep Lim, Da-sol Jeon, Won-Du Chang, and Chang-Hwan Im, 🛮 🗷 🗷 🗷 🗷 🗷 🗷
 - 50th Korean Society of Medical & Biological Engineering (KOSOMBE), Daegu, S. Korea, May 8, 2015
- 2. **Ho-Seung Cha**, Jeong-Hwan Lim, Han-Jeong Hwang, Chang-Hee Han, and Chang-Hwan Im, Development of CTVEP-based brain switch system
 - 49th Korean Society of Medical & Biological Engineering (KOSOMBE), Osong, S. Korea, Nov 9 2013
- 1. **Ho-Seung Cha**, Jeong-Hwan Lim, Han-Jeong Hwang, Chang-Hee Han, and Chang-Hwan Im, Development of transient visual evoked potential-based brain switch system
 - $48 th\ Korean\ Society\ of\ Medical\ \&\ Biological\ Engineering\ (KOSOMBE), Inchon,\ S.\ Korea,\ Nov\ 8\ 2013$

INTERNATIONAL

 Chang-Hwan Im, Ho-Seung Cha, Seong-Jun Choi, Electronic Device, Avatar Facial Expression System and Controlling Method Thereof Filed, US 16/534,579, Aug 2019. [Link]

DOMESTIC (S. KOREA)

8. Chang-Hwan Im and **Ho-Seung Cha**, Apparatus and Method for User Authentication Using Facial EMG by Measuring Changes of Facial Expression of HMD User

Issued, KR 1020944880000, Mar 2020. [Link]

7. Chang-Hwan Im and Ho-Seung Cha, Emotion Recognition Method and Device Using Electromyogram Signal

Issued, KR 10-2018-0080953, Jan 2020. [Link]

6. Won-Du Chang, Chang-Hwan Im, **Ho-Seung Cha**, Asynchronous Eye-Character Recognition Method and Apparatus Using Electromyogram Data

Issued, KR 10-2019-0124660, vol. 54, pp. 1632-1634, Oct 2019. [Link]

5. Chang-Hwan Im, Kang-Min Choi, **Ho-Seung Cha**, Method for Tracking Eye of HMD User and HMD for Tracking Eye of User

Issued, KR 10-2019-0117185, Sep 2019. [Link]

4. Chang-Hwan Im, **Ho-Seung Cha**, Seong-Jun Choi, Learning Method and Apparatus for Facial Expression Recognition, Facial Expression Recognition Method Using Electromyogram Data

Filed, KR 10-2018-0031888, Mar 2018. [Link]

3. Won-Du Chang, Chang-Hwan Im, **Ho-Seung Cha**, Kwang-Ryeol Lee, Method and System for Recognition of Eye-Character based on Tracking Technique of Electro Oculogram Gaze

Issued, KR 10-2016-0117716, Jun 2017. [Link]

2. Chang-Hwan Im, Won-Du Chang, **Ho-Seung Cha**, System and method for detecting spikes whose widths are within a certain range in time-series data

Issued, KR 10-2014-0058590, Dec 2015. [Link]

1. **Ho-Seung Cha**, Chang-Hwan Im, Jeong-Hwan Lim, Han-Jeong Hwang, Chang-Hee Han, Won-Du Chang, Method and apparatus for generating signals using transient visual evoked potential

Issued, KR 10-2013-0168546, vol. 2(4), Jul 2015. [Link]

Software _

3. Facial electromyogram-based facial expression recognition system

C-2018-036477, Dec 2018. [Click]

2. F-avatar

C-2018-036476, Dec 2018. [Click]

1. Bio-Control

C-2018-030968, Nov 2018. [Click]

Press_

3. VR Avatars Copy Your Facial Expressions. When you smile, they smile with you

News-H, Jan 2019. [Link (Korean)] [Link (English)]

2. VR Avatar looks exactly like me!

Dong-A Ilbo, Dec 2018. [Link] [Click to see the article capture]

1. Why don't we rate movie using "brainwave indices"?

DongaScience, Dec 2014 [Link]

Projects

RESEARCH PROJECTS

Recognizing facial expressions basedon facial electromyogram for interactive VR applications

Foundation @ Samsung Electronics

Samsung Science & Technology

Sep 2017 - Aug 2020

PARTICIPATING RESEARCHER

- PI: Prof. Chang-Hwan Im
- develop real-time facial expression recognition system [Click to see the paper] [Click to see the video]

Development of Non-invasive Integrated BCI SW Platform To Control Home Appliance and External Devices By User's Thought Via AR/VR Interface

Korea Institute of Science and Technology (KIST)

Apr 2017 - Dec 2020

PARTICIPATING RESEARCHER

- PI: Prof. Chang-Hwan Im
- develop emotion recognition system using facial electromyogram [Click to see the patent]

Development of Eye Tracking Source Technology Based on Electrooculogram for HCI Application

National Research Foundation

(NRF)

PARTICIPATING RESEARCHER

- · PI: Prof. Won-Du Chang
- design and conduct experiments for recording electrooculogram signals [Click to see the paper]

Development of Multimodal Brain-Machine Inference System Based on User Intent Recognition

Participating Researcher

- PI: Prof. Inyoung Kim
- develop EEG indices for predicting user's BCI application suitability [Click to see the paper]

Information & Communication Technology Promotion (IITP)

May 2013 - Feb 2017

May 2015 - Apr 2017

Development of real-time bio-signal-based cultural content evaluation technology focused on large customers

PARTICIPATING RESEARCHER

- · PI: Prof. Dong pyo Jang
- develop EEG indices for evaluating cinematics [Click to see the paper] [Click to see the news article]

Korea Institute of Industrial Technology (KITECH)

May 2013 - Feb 2016

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Key board-based braille input system for visually impaired

Developer

Yonsei University

Sep 2010 - Dec 2010

- visual programming class project (A+) @ Yonsei University.

Skills_

Data analysis experiences Bio-electric signals (EEG/EMG/EOG) · GSR · 3D motion data · Images

Research techniques Machine learning · Deep learning · Time-frequency signal analysis · Real-time signal processing

Programming Matlab · Python · C++/C

Web/Media Adobe premiere
Language Korean · English

AUGUST 24, 2020, UPDATED ANDY H. CHA · CURRICULUM VITAE

References

Chang-Hwan Im (Ph.D.)

Seoul, S. Korea

PROFESSOR, CHAIR | DEPARTMENT OF BIOMEDICAL ENGINEERING @ HANYANG UNIVERSITY

Office: +82-2-2220-2322E-mail: ich@hanyang.ac.kr

• Homapage [Click]

Won-Du Chang (Ph.D.)

Pusan, S. Korea

ASSISTANT PROFESSOR | DEPARTMENT OF COMPUTER ENGINEERING @ PUKYONG NATIONAL UNIVERSITY

Office: +82-51-629-6246e-mail: chang@pknu.ac.krHomepage [Click]

Pusan, S. Korea

YoungJin Jung (Ph.D.)

ASSISTANT PROFESSOR | DEPARTMENT OF RADIOLOGICAL SCIENCE AT HEALTH SCIENCE DIVISION @ DONGSEO UNIVERSITY

- Tell: +82-51-320-2871
- E-mail: microbme@dongseo.ac.kr
- Homepage [Click]